# YUNMEI SONG

🕋 76 Goddard Street, Providence, RI 02908 📮 401-263-5111 🛮 YSong01@wildcat.jwu.edu

## Summary

With 7 years of professional business experience in operation, management and service. Exceptional ability to solve problems, and demonstrated ability to work under pressures. Solid and diverse experience in emergency management. Proven excellent communication and negotiation skills, strong analytical and organizational skills.

### **Experience**

Project Manager, Beijing BEYOU Education and Technology Co. Ltd., Beijing, China 02/2011 - 08/2012

- Assisted in company's expansion including targeted areas evaluation and the selection of new sites in 3 metropolitan areas.
- Evaluated and negotiated with real estate developers.
- Established and retained company's public relationship with local government.

Commercial Manager, Huawei Technologies Co. Ltd, Moscow, Russia

08/2007 - 01/2011

- Assisted in business bidding and contract negotiation on projects with trade term of FOB, FCA, CIP, DDU, and DDP.
- Formulated the business model of bidding projects; analyzed and estimated the costs.
- Optimized the payment terms for a 200 million US dollars bidding project by decreasing penalty ratio, shortening the redemption period, and optimizing the acceptance process; participated in negotiation, which saved 20 million US dollars for the company.

**Administrative Manager**, Huawei Technologies Co. Ltd, Moscow, Russia

07/2006 - 08/2007

- In charge of 400+ Chinese employees' working visa in all aspects of process.
- Established visa data management system to shorten the visa application process and reduce the company's visa application cost by USD 100,000.
- Assisted Chinese employees and their families in every aspect of their living needs, such as doctor visiting, children education, etc.
- As a core coordinator, successfully organized annual company conference with 800+ attendants.
- Managed 160 sets of company's dormitory, including leasing and allocation.

#### **Education**

Johnson & Wales University, Providence, RI	09/2012-Present
MBA Leadership	GPA 3.66/4.00
Moscow Technological University, Moscow, Russia	09/2007-06/2009
M.S Project Management	GPA 3.50/4.00
Volgograd State Technical University, Volgograd, Russia	09/2002-06/2006
B.S Economics	GPA 3.65/4.00

### **Computer Skills**

Windows, MS Office, Social Media, ERP

## Language Skills

Chinese, English, Russian

### Special Skills

International Rules for the Interpretation of Trade Terms, international trade contract, international bidding experiences, financial management